<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Games on rheneross</title><link>https://blog.thibaud.io/tags/games/</link><description>Recent content in Games on rheneross</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.thibaud.io/tags/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Strike!</title><link>https://blog.thibaud.io/posts/2025_02_14/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.thibaud.io/posts/2025_02_14/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hey everyone,&lt;br>
I hope you are all doing great!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week, something really important happened in the game&amp;rsquo;s industry: &lt;strong>a Strike!&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Started by a French union&amp;mdash;the STJV&amp;mdash;the movement was also joined by CSVI-CGT in Spain. &lt;a href="https://www.stjv.fr/en/2025/02/video-game-industry-general-strike-what-demands/">You can read their demands here&lt;/a>.&lt;br>
If you want to support the effort, an &lt;a href="https://itch.io/b/2891/grve-bundle-gg25">itch.io game bundle&lt;/a> was created, with a lot of great games like &lt;strong>Pyrene&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Minami Lane&lt;/strong>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And apparently, the strike was a success!&lt;br>


&lt;blockquote class="bluesky-embed" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:drkl6rkntt57jub7gghhfjmb/app.bsky.feed.post/3li3bzj3m222z" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreidtaz3mdjgmqetnguglys6zzurpbdw2wgzaayli5efycpapjs53i4">&lt;p lang="en">🇬🇧 Today will make history in the video game industry. Strikes in 3 countries, more than 1000 people at our rallies across France, and even more on strike for our working conditions and our jobs&amp;#x27; future. The balance of power has shifted #gg25&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:drkl6rkntt57jub7gghhfjmb/post/3li3bzj3m222z?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone,<br>
I hope you are all doing great!</p>
<p>This week, something really important happened in the game&rsquo;s industry: <strong>a Strike!</strong><br>
Started by a French union&mdash;the STJV&mdash;the movement was also joined by CSVI-CGT in Spain. <a href="https://www.stjv.fr/en/2025/02/video-game-industry-general-strike-what-demands/">You can read their demands here</a>.<br>
If you want to support the effort, an <a href="https://itch.io/b/2891/grve-bundle-gg25">itch.io game bundle</a> was created, with a lot of great games like <strong>Pyrene</strong> or <strong>Minami Lane</strong>!</p>
<p>And apparently, the strike was a success!<br>


<blockquote class="bluesky-embed" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:drkl6rkntt57jub7gghhfjmb/app.bsky.feed.post/3li3bzj3m222z" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreidtaz3mdjgmqetnguglys6zzurpbdw2wgzaayli5efycpapjs53i4"><p lang="en">🇬🇧 Today will make history in the video game industry. Strikes in 3 countries, more than 1000 people at our rallies across France, and even more on strike for our working conditions and our jobs&#x27; future. The balance of power has shifted #gg25<br><br><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:drkl6rkntt57jub7gghhfjmb/post/3li3bzj3m222z?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p>&mdash; Syndicat des Travailleur·ses du Jeu Vidéo (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:drkl6rkntt57jub7gghhfjmb?ref_src=embed">@stjv.fr</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:drkl6rkntt57jub7gghhfjmb/post/3li3bzj3m222z?ref_src=embed">February 13, 2025 at 7:12 PM</a></blockquote><script async src="https://embed.bsky.app/static/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</p>
<p>The closest rally were more than 2 hours from where I live, so I observed the strike in my own way&mdash;by playing through <em>A Plague&rsquo;s Tale: Innocence</em>.<br>
I really enjoyed the game: the story hooked me right away, and I loved sneaking around guards and breaking their lanterns so they get swarmed by rats. Some said the infiltration was on rail, it didn&rsquo;t bother me at all.<br>
The only thing I found a little bit annoying was the menu to change projectiles.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve also started Kingdom Come: Deliverance, the first one.<br>
I&rsquo;m enjoying it so far, even though I must avoid an entire road because someone I&rsquo;ve beaten in a Tourney is looking to kill me with a poison blade.<br>
We&rsquo;ll see what comes next!</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s all for this week, see you all next time!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Back to work</title><link>https://blog.thibaud.io/posts/2025_01_10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.thibaud.io/posts/2025_01_10/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s time to look back on the first work week of 2025 :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First I had this &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kYtGl1dX5qI">old song&lt;/a> stuck in my head for most of the week. Sorry, I had to &lt;em>let it all out&lt;/em>!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="morning-pages">Morning Pages&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve started writing three A4 pages every morning before work. It&amp;rsquo;s excruciating&amp;mdash;I dread the moment all the way to my office&amp;mdash;but &lt;em>boy&lt;/em> does it feel good when it&amp;rsquo;s done.
It&amp;rsquo;s all coming from the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Artist%27s_Way">Artist&amp;rsquo;s Way&lt;/a> by Julia Cameron, and while I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy the spiritual aspects of the book, I find the method interesting. I will be continuing the exercises through the start of the year, and try to report back on my progress here.&lt;/p></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s time to look back on the first work week of 2025 :)</p>
<p>First I had this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kYtGl1dX5qI">old song</a> stuck in my head for most of the week. Sorry, I had to <em>let it all out</em>!</p>
<h2 id="morning-pages">Morning Pages</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;ve started writing three A4 pages every morning before work. It&rsquo;s excruciating&mdash;I dread the moment all the way to my office&mdash;but <em>boy</em> does it feel good when it&rsquo;s done.
It&rsquo;s all coming from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Artist%27s_Way">Artist&rsquo;s Way</a> by Julia Cameron, and while I don&rsquo;t enjoy the spiritual aspects of the book, I find the method interesting. I will be continuing the exercises through the start of the year, and try to report back on my progress here.</p>
<h2 id="multi-project-ing">Multi-project-ing</h2>
<p>Already, I found a positive side-effect of the morning pages: they help me sort my thoughts before starting the day.<br>
That &ldquo;<em>enlightenment</em>&rdquo; also pushed me to change the way I juggle my multiple projects.</p>
<p>Previously, I merged all my tasks into one massive todo list then, every morning, I would sit at my desk and select the tasks I needed to work on for the day&mdash;then proceed to work all day on completely different things.</p>
<p>Now, each task lives in a different place:</p>
<ul>
<li>Personal / Administrative tasks: in Todoist, which I sort and prioritize every now and then</li>
<li>Client tasks: in the client task management system</li>
<li>Personal project tasks: in their own repository</li>
</ul>
<p>Now, every morning, after writing my pages, I check with myself if I want to work on one project or another, then proceed to work on tasks related to this project.<br>
If something urgent needs to be done, it&rsquo;s usually top of mind, so I handle it immediately.</p>
<p>With this new organization, I no longer feel like like I&rsquo;m behind on tasks. Instead, I&rsquo;m more focused on what I want to work one&mdash;like BugBee!</p>
<h2 id="bugbee">BugBee</h2>
<p><a href="https://bugbee.app">BugBee</a> is a Discord bot designed to help studios manage game feedback and bug reports efficiently. Currently, it allows you to gather player inputs directly from Discord.</p>
<p>With the next update&mdash;which should be live next week&mdash;I&rsquo;m adding an API that lets developers integrate feedback submission directly from their games. All reports will be funneled into the same Discord feedback channel, making it easy to track them. It&rsquo;s the final feature I wanted before actively talking about it!</p>
<h2 id="game1-pre-production">Game1 Pre-Production</h2>
<p>I also made some progress on selecting a content workflow for my next game. My current prototype, built with Godot + <a href="https://github.com/func-godot/func_godot_plugin">FuncGodot</a> + <a href="https://trenchbroom.github.io/">TrenchBroom</a>, works really well for what I want to achieve, buuuuut I wanted to try one last approach: I&rsquo;m experimenting with a prototype built without Godot, instead using <a href="https://odin-lang.org/">Odin</a> + <a href="https://github.com/floooh/sokol">Sokol</a> and having it load bsp maps from <a href="https://ficool2.github.io/HammerPlusPlus-Website/">Hammer++</a>.
I really like working without an editor&mdash;except for making maps obviously.</p>
<p>That said, I really need to get better at making levels :)</p>
<h2 id="i-also-played-some-games">I also played some games</h2>
<h3 id="enshrouded">Enshrouded</h3>
<p>This week, I tried Enshrouded with some friends and we all enjoyed it!<br>
What I like about it:</p>
<ul>
<li>Same feeling of exploration I had with Valheim, but less punitive</li>
<li>Magic chests that act as a remote inventory for crafting</li>
<li>Meaningful loots from monsters, not everything is obtained by crafting</li>
</ul>
<p>Things I don&rsquo;t like that much:</p>
<ul>
<li>Using NPC for crafting, I spend my time in base looking for them</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="balatro">Balatro</h3>
<p>I know I&rsquo;m late to the Balatro party, but I&rsquo;m glad I finally came: it&rsquo;s a hell of a party!<br>
Like everyone else, I&rsquo;m addicted!</p>
<hr>
<p>I believe that&rsquo;s all for this week!<br>
Talk to you next time :)</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Here we go again</title><link>https://blog.thibaud.io/posts/2024_12_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:08:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.thibaud.io/posts/2024_12_2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been journaling daily for about 10 years and, even in the privacy of my notebook, it&amp;rsquo;s been incredibly effective at taming the beast inside my head. Sometimes, though, I feel the urge to write something public and share it with the void.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, the urge returned: I&amp;rsquo;ve been fixating on ways to cooperate differently, especially in the game industry, and I had to get it out of my system. My previous attempt at a blog was retired at the time, so I went for the fastest way to publish anything: a newsletter platform. I wrote two articles, and then the emails flooded in. &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Grow your audience fast with fastaudiencegrowth&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>, &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Subscribe to our premium platform and win your subscribers&amp;rsquo; weight in gold.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been journaling daily for about 10 years and, even in the privacy of my notebook, it&rsquo;s been incredibly effective at taming the beast inside my head. Sometimes, though, I feel the urge to write something public and share it with the void.</p>
<p>Recently, the urge returned: I&rsquo;ve been fixating on ways to cooperate differently, especially in the game industry, and I had to get it out of my system. My previous attempt at a blog was retired at the time, so I went for the fastest way to publish anything: a newsletter platform. I wrote two articles, and then the emails flooded in. <em>&ldquo;Grow your audience fast with fastaudiencegrowth&rdquo;</em>, <em>&ldquo;Subscribe to our premium platform and win your subscribers&rsquo; weight in gold.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>Begone, devil! The void is my audience, and it shall not grow!</p>
<p>So, I dug back out my old blog, dusted it off, and published it again. I migrated the two articles and reclaimed my digital ownership! I even kept my old posts from 2022 — though I wouldn’t recommend diving too deep into them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I was lucky to have my roots in websites because I always understood the value of building my own online spaces, and hosting everything that mattered to me on my own sites.<br>
— <!-- raw HTML omitted --><a href="https://www.nathalielawhead.com/candybox/positive-feedback-loops-the-power-of-choice-digital-independence-and-building-something-better-for-everyone">Nathalie Lawhead</a><!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
</blockquote>
<p>I have always value my digital independence, and I self-host a lot of services. I also believe that, as long as you control the source material, not everything needs to be <em>strictly</em> self-hosted. For example, this blog is a static site hosted on github pages and, even if github stop offering the service, I can move it somewhere else without loosing anything.</p>
<p>Aside from that, I&rsquo;ve been playing through my backlog a lot lately:</p>
<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;ve finished Portal Stories: Mel, a nice story for people wanting more Portal.</li>
<li>I&rsquo;ve played a couple of chapters of Black Mesa, astonishing work!</li>
<li>I enjoyed Tinyfolks a lot. It&rsquo;s a tiny, more forgiving, Darkest Dungeon.</li>
<li>Clickholding: this one I can&rsquo;t say anything about, you&rsquo;d have to see it for yourself.</li>
<li>And lastly, I&rsquo;ve just started DREDGE, but I love it already :)</li>
</ul>
<p>Tinyfolks especially motivated me to start working on a tiny game - we&rsquo;ll see were it leads!</p>
<p>Until then, have a nice week and see you next time!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>